Yerassyl Seilkhanov

+747 1117711

yseilkhanov@gmail.com
Linkedin | Telegram

Experienced **Production Planning Specialist** with over 3 years of experience in managing production **schedules, inventory control, and resource allocation.** Adept at utilizing software systems such as **SAP PP** to optimize supply chain processes and improve efficiency. Strong problemsolving skills and ability to work under tight deadlines.

EDUCATION

MEnvSc

<u>Università Ca' Foscari Venezia</u> 2021 – 2023

B.S. in Petroleum Engineering

Kazakh-British Technical
University
2014-2018

National School of Physics & Math (FIZMAT) 2014

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Certifications

- Six sigma: Green Belt
- SQL for Marketers and Product Managers
- Supervised Machine
 Learning:
 Regression and
 Classification

Languages

- · Native Kazakh
- Proficiency Russian
- · Advanced English

Courses

- · Data Analysis with Python
- Materials Requirement Planning (MRP)
- Project Management

KEY SKILLS

Instruments: Excel, Google Sheets, MRP software (SAP PP), SQL, Python, Jira **Methods**: Knowledge of production processes and operations, Lean Manufacturing and Six Sigma methodologies, Production and Maintenance Scheduling, Strong analytical and problem-solving skills, Project Management Time Management, Cross-Functional Collaboration.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Planning and Control Specialist

Patentes Talgo S.L. Almaty, Kazakhstan · 2022 – Jan. 2023

- Managed production schedules and allocated resources to ensure efficient utilization of resources and on-time delivery of goods.
- · Rolling stock maintenance planning and control.
- Improved support metrics based on employees hours and material consumption data.
- Monitored and adjusted inventory levels to ensure optimal stock levels while minimizing carrying costs.
- Scheduling overhauls, controlling & optimization of the processes, preparing line for the one-piece flow applying Lean (5s, Kanban, Kaizen, Poka Yoke and e.t.c) and FastWork tools.
- Worked closely with cross-functional teams to resolve production and supply chain issues.

Environmental Project Planner

Saipem S.P.A. · Marghera VE, Italy · 2021 – 2022

- Planned and supervised a project for the collection of environmental data in the area of the industrial zone of Marghera, Venice.
- Led tasks related to environmental data collection, research, documentation, and technical analyses.
- Prepared and developed feasibility and supporting studies for environmental planning projects.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, such as engineers and scientists, to ensure that environmental concerns are considered in project design and implementation.

Maintenance Engineer

<u>Intergas Central Asia JSC</u> · Almaty, Kazakhstan · 2018 – 2020

- Managed maintenance projects, including budgeting, scheduling and supervision of technicians.
- Troubleshot and repaired mechanical, electrical, and plumbing systems to minimize equipment downtime.
- Maintained accurate equipment maintenance records and inventory control of spare parts.
- Launched of plans for the maintenance works. in 3 districts of Almaty for preventive measures
- -Lead Kaizen improvement efforts and mentor others in formal process of problem solving